ADAM JULIER

Software Engineer / Web Developer

(203) 947-4371 | Eastchester, NY 10709 | atjulier@gmail.com AdamTJ.com

Summary

- Full-stack software developer with a versatile background & experience using modern web frameworks.
- Experience in developing client-side applications, as well as creating/consuming REST APIs.
- Passion for learning. High attention to detail. Proficient working as part of a team, as well as autonomously.

Technical Tools & Skills

JavaScript, React.js, React Native, NodeJS, Express, Python, Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, Redux, Swift/XCode, jQuery, Bootstrap, UX Optimization, Content Management Systems, Regex, JWT, PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Application Deployment, Unit Testing, Version Control (Git)

Professional Experience

McMahon Medical Group – New York, NY (2016 - Jan 2018)

(Multiple properties including: AnesthesiologyNews.com, GeneralSurgeryNews.com, & more) Web Analyst

- Co-created & designed the database infrastructure for an internal web app which aggregates data from multiple external sources
- Creating reporting templates for medical advertising clients with detailed campaign metrics
- Analyzing and finding ways to improve key performance metrics including ad impressions, pageviews, ad clicks, eNewsletter open rates, ad viewability, reducing invalid/non-human traffic
- Managing web ads so that all are able to reach clients' goals, & deploying eNewsletter campaigns

Web Development, SEO, Digital Analytics – Self-Employed Contractor (2015 - 2016)

• Creating/updating sites & web apps built to clients' desired specifications, while also offering suggestions & digital strategies based on knowledge of best development practices, SEO, etc.

Parchem–Fine & Specialty Chemicals - New Rochelle, NY (2013 - 2015)

Data Engineer

- Managing all product data on multiple web properties, using SQL and custom content management systems (CMS) to maintain backend databases
- Creation of various automation macros, scripts, tools, databases, reports, and forms used by salespeople/staff
- Creating & maintaining an internal resource page using HTML/CSS/JS
- Implementing SEO strategies in order to maintain & increase position as a top-ranking site in the industry
- Optimizing conversion rates using keyword performance, A/B testing, heat maps, referrer traffic data, etc.

Education

Web Development Immersive – General Assembly – New York, New York (Mar - Jun 2018)

• A 3-month full-time intensive program covering the in-depth processes of developing full-stack web applications using JavaScript, React.js, Node & Express, Ruby on Rails, and more

University at Albany - Albany, New York (May 2012)

• Bachelor of Arts in Economics, with coursework in Computer Science